<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[INTERSECTIONS]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.bajake.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.bajake.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-10T00:15:42-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.bajake.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jake Bailey]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2014/01/31/changes/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-31T08:51:05-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.bajake.com/blog/2014/01/31/changes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been almost a year since I published anything on this blog and feel it is time to again make this a regular space to put down my thoughts.</p>

<p>Many things have changed since March of last year, most notably moving from the sun drenched state of Colorado, of which I have called home for the last 26 years, to the optimistic and beautiful city by the bay, San Francisco, California.</p>

<p>A handful of reasons led to this life altering event but now that I have been here for almost nine months, the risk has already paid off ten fold. The people, the ideas, the entrepreneurship, the food, the scenery have all led me to believe this is hands down the most perfect place for me to be at this point in my life.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Being an idealist in which I believe technology can make the world a better place, I felt it quite imperative to find a job in the heart of what some are calling the <a href="http://www.kqed.org/a/forum/R201401271000" target="_blank">second machine age</a>. Silicon Valley is like no other place on earth and for years I was watching as <a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424053111903480904576512250915629460" target="_blank">software was eating the world</a> from the <a href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/19/how-tesla-netflix-and-nest-are-using-smart-data-to-completely-redefine-the-game/">sidelines</a>. If I were to help contribute to the bettering of society through technology and innovative thinking, it was time to become a little over my head and surround myself with the <a href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/03/12/the-smartest-people-in-the-internet-chat-room/">smartest people I could find</a>.</p>

<p>Once the decision to move to the bay area was complete, the next steps were finding a company that shared the same values that I did. Drive, Integrity, Compassion. After lack of openings at the various companies I already admired in the area, I ran across this amazingly refreshing video from LinkedIn&rsquo;s CEO Jeff Wiener. (It is bit long at 40 minutes but well worth your time investment.)</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.bajake.com//www.youtube.com/embed/2x0fOLqj2Zw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>I was blown away! If this was the thought process of the leader of the company, I couldn&rsquo;t even imagine what it was like to work there. I immediately logged on to LinkedIn, a place where I was spending more and more time throughout my job search, and began looking at openings at LinkedIn itself. How meta. I immediately found a job perfectly suited for my skills and background and saved it for later. I knew I would have to write a kick ass cover letter to get my foot in the door at such an influential company.</p>

<p>A few days later, I was visiting some friends in Chapel Hill, North Carolina, and penned this cover letter while sitting in the UNC library. I had no idea if it would even be read. Yet to my surprise, a couple days later I received a call from one of LinkedIn&rsquo;s recruiters.</p>

<p>After a second phone interview and a visit to the campus, I received a job offer. The dream had become a reality. I packed up my car, headed west and the rest they say is history.</p>

<p>Now that I have finally settled in, I plan to share more thoughts on LinkedIn&rsquo;s incredible management style, the local tech industry as well as how my interest in minimalism permeates through all of the above.</p>

<p>Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Smartest People in the (Internet Chat) Room]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/03/12/the-smartest-people-in-the-internet-chat-room/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-12T22:17:31-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/03/12/the-smartest-people-in-the-internet-chat-room</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Always work with the smartest people you can find, and always be in a little over your head.</p><footer><strong>Marissa Mayer, CEO of Yahoo</strong> <cite><a href='http://nymag.com/thecut/2012/10/marissa-mayer-yahoo-ceo.html'>New York Magazine Interview</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>I take this advice to heart everyday and do my best to surround myself with smart people. I also like to follow and read people who not only inspire me but are some of the smartest and most successful tech people in the world. Below is a short list of people who I enjoy right now.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://37signals.com/svn/writers/jf" target="_blank">Jason Fried</a> &ndash; Building products and cultures at <a href="http://37signals.com" target="_blank"> 37Signals</a>, a company that is bootstrapped, profitable and proud.</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Bezos" target="_blank">Jeff Bezos</a> &ndash; The true king of the <a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/moneybox/2013/01/29/amazon_q4_profits_fall_45_percent.html" target="_blank">long term company strategy.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.feld.com/wp/" target="_blank">Brad Feld</a> &ndash; Managing director of Boulder based <a href="http://www.foundrygroup.com/wp/" target="_blank">Foundry Group.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.swiss-miss.com/" target="_blank">Tina Roth Eisenberg</a> &ndash; Super blogger known as swissmiss and a testament that side projects can lead to <a href="http://www.tattly.com" target="_blank">great businesses.</a></li>
<li><a href="http://bijansabet.com/" target="_blank">Bijan Sabet</a> &ndash; Great photographer and general partner at <a href="http://www.sparkcapital.com/" target="_blank">Spark Capital</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/jack" target="_blank">Jack Dorsey</a> &ndash; Co-founder of Twitter and CEO of <a href="https://squareup.com/" target="_blank">Square</a>. He understands that technology can be beautiful.</li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tony_Hsieh" target="_blank">Tony Hsei</a> &ndash; Tony takes <a href="http://www.deliveringhappiness.com/about-us/about-2/" target="_blank">company culture</a> very seriously. It paid off when Amazon bought Zappos for $1 billion.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.salesforce.com/company/leadership/executive-team/#benioff" target="_blank">Mark Benoiff</a> &ndash; Pioneered the <a href="http://www.salesforcefoundation.org/sharethemodel" target="_blank">1-1-1</a> business model and runs Salesforce.com, one of the most <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/victoriabarret/2012/09/05/why-salesforce-com-ranks-1-on-forbes-most-innovative-list/" target="_blank">innovative companies</a> in the world.</li>
<li><a href="http://cdixon.org/" target="_blank">Chris Dixon</a> &ndash; Entrepreneur turned VC at <a href="http://a16z.com/" target="_blank">Andersson Horowitz</a>.</li>
<li><a href="https://twitter.com/levie" target="_blank">Aaron Levie</a> &ndash; Humor and hard work pay off for the CEO of <a href="http://www.box.com" target="_blank">Box.com</a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://elonmusk.com/" target="_blank">Elon Musk</a> &ndash; He is the inspiration for Tony Stark in the Iron Man movies for good reason. <a href="http://www.paypal.com" target="_blank">PayPal</a>, <a href="http://www.spacex.com" target="_blank">SpaceX</a>, <a href="http://www.tesla.com" target="_blank">Tesla</a> and <a href="http://www.solarcity.com/" target="_blank">Solar City</a>.</li>
</ul>


<p>This list would not be complete without Steve Jobs so I will end with one of my favorite quotes. This is from his father and influenced him the rest of his life.</p>

<blockquote><p>When you’re a carpenter making a beautiful chest of drawers, you’re not going to use a piece of plywood on the back, even though it faces the wall and nobody will ever see it. You’ll know it’s there, so you’re going to use a beautiful piece of wood in the back. For you to sleep well at night, the aesthetic, the quality, has to be carried all the way through.</p></blockquote>

<p>Who inspires you on a daily basis?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Setup]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/23/the-setup/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-23T21:17:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/23/the-setup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For years, I have been a fan and follower of <a href="http://www.usethis.com" target="_blank"> The Setup</a>, a blog dedicated to interviewing various people on their computer hardware and software setups. Everyone from chefs to programmers to cosplayers (something I didn’t even know existed) have been featured. Being someone who is fascinated by how technology interacts with everyday life, The Setup does a great job of asking simple questions to get to the core of what people think about the technology/tools they use everyday and where they could be taken in the future.</p>

<p>Since I am definitely not important enough to end up on the site, I thought I would share what I use to get stuff done.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>Who are you, and what do you do?</h3>

<p>Hi, I’m Jake Bailey and I am the Technology and Operations manager for SlimGenics, a health and wellness company headquartered in Denver, CO. Being a native, I do everything I can to take advantage of the 300+ days of sunshine a year. Activities include but are not limited to hiking, camping, skiing and biking (mountain and road). I am also a connoisseur of sandwiches and a minimalist in training.</p>

<h3>What hardware do you use?</h3>

<p>Currently I enjoy a 2011 Core i7 Macbook Air that my current company provided me. It has a 250GB SSD drive and 4 GB of memory and runs Mountain Lion, all which offer plenty of power, storage and flexibility for the limited amount of strain I put on the system. At the office I connect this to a 27-inch Thunderbolt Display, a Magic Mouse and a full size Apple wired keyboard. I have found the wireless keyboards eat batteries for breakfast.</p>

<p>I am addicted to my iPhone 5. This is one of my favorite possessions because it is my portable window into the entire world.</p>

<p>I recently received an iPad as a gift and to tell you the truth, I only use it to surf the web on the couch or read an article or two at breakfast. I tend to find myself reaching for my Kindle more and more these days due to the fact that I can disconnect and focus on reading.</p>

<p>I write notes and ideas in a graphed hardcover Moleskin notebook and watch Netflix and stream music on my AppleTV.</p>

<p>Finally, all portables get put into a Chrome Citizen Bag while I ride around town on an 80’s Centurion Sport DLX bicycle.</p>

<h3>What software do you use?</h3>

<h4>Work</h4>

<p>On the job I live in Salesforce.com for company analytics and marketing automation, ExactTarget for sending and tracking emails, Magento to access and manage the company website, Basecamp for project management, Evernote for taking notes, and Gchat for interacting with my team of developers that work remotely.</p>

<h4>Personal</h4>

<p>At home, Twitter is my news source, Simple is my new bank and finance app, Spotify has completely replaced iTunes for music, Adobe Creative Suite powers through design projects and Sublime 2 and the very simple Terminal.app are used for my increasing interest in development.</p>

<p>Finally, everything is backed up to either Dropbox or Amazon’s S3 using Arq.</p>

<h4>What is your dream set-up?</h4>

<p>I am actually pretty satisfied with my current set-up for the time being. However, since this is a dream, here is what it would look like.</p>

<p>On the hardware side, I would really like a Macbook Air with a higher resolution display and LTE built in so I could use it anywhere. Having it tether to my iPhone would be nice too, that way I’m not paying ATT more then necessary. Actually free, citywide WiFi would be better…</p>

<p>On the software front, I think it would be great if I could store my entire computer (apps, settings, files, software, etc) all in the cloud where it could be accessed from any device. A virtual server of sorts except for your personal computer. I want to be able to work anywhere, with any machine at any time without having to worry about what software is where.</p>

<p>Also, no wires for anything, including charging. I despise having to remember to bring various chargers with me everywhere I go. Free, citywide WiFi charging perhaps?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Tesla, Netflix and Nest Are Using Smart Data to Completely Redefine the Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/19/how-tesla-netflix-and-nest-are-using-smart-data-to-completely-redefine-the-game/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-19T21:16:53-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/19/how-tesla-netflix-and-nest-are-using-smart-data-to-completely-redefine-the-game</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The last few weeks have provided a unique look behind the curtain of how a few companies are using connected networks and devices to completely redefine the markets they compete in. No longer are we just talking about how cheap storage or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_data" target="_blank">Big Data</a> will change the business landscape, we are actually living it. New companies, run by connected, technologically savvy leaders are putting data first and reaping the rewards in surprisingly unique ways.</p>

<h3>The Internet of Things has Officially Arrived!</h3>

<p>Before we look at what these companies are doing, I think a little history lesson is in order.</p>

<p>The concept of the “Internet of Things” (IoT) was <a href="http://www.rfidjournal.com/articles/view?4986" target="_blank">first introduced</a> over a decade ago, when in 1999, Kevin Ashton gave a presentation to Proctor &amp; Gamble in which he linked the new idea of RFID tags with the still then emerging Internet. Needless to say, his presentation succeeded in getting executive attention focused on their supply chain. Now, 14 years later, Kevin’s overarching concept is finally starting to take shape,</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The general idea was that if we had computers that knew everything there was to know about things—using data they gathered without any help from us—we would be able to track and count everything, and greatly reduce waste, loss and cost. We would know when things needed replacing, repairing or recalling, and whether they were fresh or past their best. The Internet of Things has the potential to change the world, just as the Internet did. Maybe even more so.”</p></blockquote>

<p>Data capture and storage has vastly improved since 1999 and what recent news is proving is that we are hitting a tipping point for how data is being used to not only differentiate companies from the competition but how it is vastly improving the world around us.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>He Who Owns the Data, Owns the Future</h3>

<h4>Tesla</h4>

<p>One of the bigger stories to come out this last week was the back and forth between New York Times columnist John Broder and Elon Musk, founder of Tesla Motors. The disagreement came about when John Broder wrote a <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/10/automobiles/stalled-on-the-ev-highway.html?ref=automobiles&_r=1&" target="_blank">scathing review</a> of the poor battery life in the new Model S electric sedan. Musk <a href="http://www.teslamotors.com/blog/most-peculiar-test-drive" target="_blank">refuted the claims</a> by provided detailed driving records of John Broder’s entire trip. There is a <a href="http://www.thewire.com/technology/2013/02/elon-musks-data-doesnt-back-his-claims-new-york-times-fakery/62149/" target="_blank">whole discussion</a> on who was actually right in this argument, but what interests me most is that this type of discussion is actually happening.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p><a href="https://twitter.com/Jason">@Jason</a> Actually, I&#39;m not questioning anyone&#39;s data. I am just observing that it is fascinating that data is now fact.</p>&mdash; Nick Bilton (@nickbilton) <a href="https://twitter.com/nickbilton/statuses/302134592389922817">February 14, 2013</a></blockquote>


<script async src="http://www.bajake.com//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>Nick Bilton, a tech writer at the New York Times tried to defend his colleagues story by asking how the data was collected in the first place. While a valid point, Musk’s charts definitely seem to have more authority then Broder’s words.</p>

<p>When I get into my trusty 2003 Honda Civic, you know what I can track? My speed, how much gas I have left and the distance I have traveled. That’s it, and that is if I look at the dashboard. Less then 10 years later, Tesla owners can now track and interact with almost every aspect of their car from an app on their phone. Telsa even issued their first <a href="http://www.wired.com/autopia/2012/09/tesla-over-the-air/" target="_blank">over the air</a> update to the Model S’s software last fall. This is the future of the automotive market. GM, Ford, Toyota and the other car companies now just get to play catch-up to an electric car company.</p>

<h4>Netflix</h4>

<p>The movie by mail/movie by internet company has also been getting a lot of press recently, mostly for their bold move to release their new show, “House of Cards” all at once. Why did they do this? What makes them so certain that this new way of distributing television will catch on? Well, as you can guess, they have data to back up their decision.</p>

<p>Slate’s Andrew Leonard addresses these ideas in the Big Brother sounding <a href="http://www.salon.com/2013/02/01/how_netflix_is_turning_viewers_into_puppets/" target="_blank">“How Netflix is turning viewers into puppets”</a>. It is no secret that Netflix is a <a href="http://readwrite.com/2011/07/26/netflixs_big_data_plans_to_take_over_the_world#awesm=~ou1Gjco76AmBjX" target="_blank">data behemoth</a>. Now it is finally using what it has learned to compete with the likes of traditional TV and HBO, the reigning go to source for high quality small screen entertainment. With the ability to monitor when we rate, watch or even pause a show, Netflix is learning what we like.</p>

<p>Of course, this is what TV has been doing for decade, putting a new show out, monitoring Nielson data, then alter the offering. Wash, rinse, repeat. Like Mr. Leonard states, why else is there a hundred different vampire or zombie shows on right now? Because it sells. What makes Netflix different is how deep it can actually go with the data. Before it was just themes, now it comes down to if we like to “mainline” our TV shows as opposed to spreading them out over weeks. This type of analysis is the birthplace for new ideas and innovation. Offering a show all at once in my mind is an entirely new type of entertainment. Sure I can watch a 2 hour movie or a 30 minute sitcom but what about a 10 hour drama with true character development and a plot line that can twist and turn for seasons on end. That is something that excites me.</p>

<p>With all this data though, will new programming be decided by algorithms instead of the artistic vision of a director? Will we be getting robot produced TV? Mr. Leonard thinks that may be the case. As Steve Jobs said,</p>

<blockquote><p>It’s really hard to design products by focus groups. A lot of times, people don’t know what they want until you show it to them.</p></blockquote>

<p>And to this I say behavior is much more valuable then asking someone what they like. Data is just going to be another tool in a director’s toolbox and hopefully content will become better and more targeted because of it.</p>

<p>While we won’t know if this strategy will help Netflix’s bottom line until the financials come out next quarter, I am looking forward to where this space is going and I applaud them for taking the risk to enter the ring first.</p>

<h4>Nest</h4>

<p>Sexy thermostats. Two words that were never even put together in a sentence before Tony Fadell and Matt Rodgers redefined the genre in 2010. In a <a href="http://www.technologyreview.com/featuredstory/511086/how-nests-control-freaks-reinvented-the-thermostat/" target="_blank">new article</a> released by MIT’s Technology Review, we learn that Nest was founded after Tony, a former Apple executive, decided to build a fully connected and future proof home. When it came to purchase a high end thermostat to control the systems in the house, he was baffled that they cost upwards of $500 a piece and were essentially brain-dead. He thought he could build a better one himself, and so he did.</p>

<p>Now, almost three years later, Nest has sold hundreds of thousands of their new thermostats and saved users $29 million in energy bills. Quite an achievement for something that just sits on the wall. By providing an easy interface and a simple concept, turning the temperature up or down, Nest has taken what is essentially an on/off switch and made it smart. Also by selling the device directly to consumers, which is a different approach then leading HVAC companies like Honeywell or Venstar who sell through distributors, Nest can use data to watch how the device is used and adapt.</p>

<blockquote><p>For example, Nest thermostats originally adjusted themselves to an energy-conserving setting in the morning two hours after detecting that human activity in a home had stopped. They waited that long in case the owner soon returned home. But anonymous data from Nest thermostats revealed that people reliably stayed out for quite a while when they left in the morning. So the company sent a software update to all the thermostats to take that into account. Now the devices turn themselves down after just 30 minutes.</p></blockquote>

<p>This new way of heating and cooling in the home has made the data lacking incumbents very scared as well. Honeywell, which <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/dividendchannel/2013/02/19/honeywell-international-takes-over-58-spot-from-monsanto/" target="_blank">just recently</a> became the 58th largest company on the S&amp;P 500, has recently sued 150 person Nest for patent infringement. The case is still being worked out in the courts, but whatever the outcome, Nest’s data set has a huge head start on the competition.</p>

<p>Lastly, Nest, even more so then Tesla or Netflix, is the perfect example of Kevin Ashton’s Internet of Things. A simple disc on the wall is teaching people how to save energy, save money and could eventually help power a more responsive smart grid in the United States. If that isn’t the definition of changing the world, then I don’t know what is.</p>

<h4>Final Thoughts</h4>

<p>All this use of smart data and innovation is only valuable if it can be sustained long term. So while stock price is only one way to look at company success, I think it does a decent job of outlining market share, stockholder value and if the company has a future.</p>

<ul>
<li>Tesla’s stock price, since going public in June 2010, is up 105%. (Full disclosure &ndash; I am an extremely small investor.)</li>
<li>Netflix’s stock, while still recovering from the Qwikster incident in 2011, is up 112% year to date.</li>
<li>Nest, a private company who doesn’t release financial figures has released sales figures “in the mid-hundreds of thousands” as of September 2012.</li>
</ul>


<p>Exciting times!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do.]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/16/do/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-16T21:16:33-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/16/do</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A solid recipe for success.</p>

<blockquote><p>Wake up early. Show up. Learn how to think. Be genuine, but appear nice. Use envy for motivation instead of destruction. Do what you say you’re going to do. Ensure balance in every area of your life. Confront repressed thoughts immediately. Surround yourself with people who are better than you (but remember the thing about envy). Work out every day. Be good at what you do. Make money doing what you love. Have good friends. Never settle.</p><footer><strong>Dustin Curtis</strong> <cite><a href='http://dcurt.is/do'>Do</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Some additions I would like to add:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Travel and experience points of view different from your own</em></li>
<li><em>Sit back and enjoy the moment as often as possible</em></li>
<li><em>Read</em></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress - Coding for N00bs]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/15/octopress-coding-for-n00bs/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T21:16:12-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.bajake.com/blog/2013/02/15/octopress-coding-for-n00bs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When it comes to coding, I am what the interwebs refer to as a newbie, a newcomer, a novice. Sure, I took an HTML class in college and made a few crappy websites but since then, all I have been able to do is go into some content management system (CMS) and change a few lines of HTML or CSS. I have never really understood how it all works. A few months ago, I decided to attempt a change in my ignorance.</p>

<p>Since I use applications, websites, and databases everyday in my job, I know good technology when I see it. <a href="http://techcrunch.com/2012/04/26/jack-dorsey-talks-square-twitter-and-instagram-facebook-with-charlie-rose/">Jack Dorsey</a>, the founder of Twitter and Square, says it best,</p>

<blockquote><p>The best technologies disappear, they fade into the background and are relevant when you use them and get out of the way when you don’t.</p></blockquote>

<p>That is a great saying but how do you create the application in the first place? I needed somewhere to start.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>After much searching I stumbled upon a great site by Zed A. Shaw who promised that <a href="http://learncodethehardway.org/">I could learn to code the hard way</a>. I was intrigued and jumped right in. That once scary terminal program and I became good friends and like a boy and his hunting dog, we were shooting down python exercises left and right. <code>print</code> this, <code>import</code> that, it was great! Then all of a sudden I stopped. I didn’t really want to go on. For weeks, I couldn’t figure out why I didn’t want to learn to code anymore. Then it hit me, I wasn’t actually creating anything tangible. These exercises were great learning tools but I never felt satisfied with the little bit of basic python knowledge I accumulated. I needed to learn and create at the same time.</p>

<p><a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</a> to the rescue! Here is an application that is based off Ruby, uses Jekyll, ties with GitHub and Heroku and even introduces the concepts of Markdown. Also, in order to create new posts, I have to get reacquainted with my friend the terminal. Finally a tangible challenge! It took me a few days to follow the directions but I now have a blog that I can be proud of, all while learning a shit ton about how it all works. I even customized the theme to <a href="http://wynnnetherland.com/journal/octopress-classic-is-the-new-kubrick">differentiate myself</a>.</p>

<p>The blog you see before you will be a playground for my continued coding education as well as a place to post my thoughts and ideas on how technology and the physical world intersect, hence the name. So while I am most likely still considered a newbie in the coding world, I look forward to where the rabbit hole will take me next.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
